[SPEAKER_01]: I broke into Martinsburg.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, you don't remember him.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was in Bill Alden's place at the base one time from Cincinnati Reds.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's back to way back.
[SPEAKER_01]: About 1920 was that?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, hell, it was 1920 when I was in Martinsburg, yes.
[SPEAKER_01]: He lived up there, coached me, and took me to Martinsburg.
[SPEAKER_02]: You were in Lycoming, were you?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, lacos.
[SPEAKER_01]: They kept it off.
[SPEAKER_01]: Lonicos.
[SPEAKER_02]: Lonicos?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, L-O-N-A-C-O-N-I-N-G. And you were pitching sandlot ball there when they saw you?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: This fellow, Loudins?
[SPEAKER_02]: Bill Loudins.
[SPEAKER_02]: Loudins saw you there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Now, was he connected with any organization?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, he wasn't in the Managed Martinsburg Club.
[SPEAKER_02]: He took me with him.
[SPEAKER_01]: I see, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Martinsburg, West Virginia.
[SPEAKER_01]: Blue Ridge League.
[SPEAKER_01]: How'd you do there?
[SPEAKER_01]: I wasn't there very long.
[SPEAKER_02]: I went to Baltimore.
[SPEAKER_01]: Jack Dunn's son scouted me a lot up there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Jack Dunn's son saw you in Martinsburg?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: I only pitched six games up in Marble Ridge.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was it quite a thrill for you to be playing professional baseball there?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, I didn't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, it's true, it's been a bit of a stretch since I've been home, but... Yeah, I went to Baltimore early.
[SPEAKER_02]: What did your parents think about you going to Pro Bowl?
[SPEAKER_02]: I didn't think that about it.
[SPEAKER_02]: What did your father do?
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a coal miner.
[SPEAKER_02]: I see.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was he pretty pleased you'd be going into the bar?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I guess.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't get back home until after the season before the ball went on.
[SPEAKER_00]: I've got your record here.
[SPEAKER_02]: You know this book.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: One thing's puzzled me.
[SPEAKER_02]: Why, when you had such a fine record at Baltimore, you won over 100 ballgames there.
[SPEAKER_02]: 111, was it?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, 108, 108.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's a pretty good number, over 100.
[SPEAKER_02]: Why weren't you up in the big time in the games?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, them days, there was no drafting in there internationally.
[SPEAKER_01]: Couldn't draft us out.
[SPEAKER_01]: Couldn't draft you.
[SPEAKER_01]: When we'd win pennants there, we'd have to make more money in Baltimore.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now for different ball clubs in the big leagues, we didn't get paid well in Baltimore for minor league club.
[SPEAKER_01]: There was one seven straight penalty there.
[SPEAKER_02]: I know.
[SPEAKER_02]: You think that Baltimore team could have played in the big league?
[SPEAKER_01]: In those days, yes, because we whipped every big league club from down there.
[SPEAKER_01]: We had a ballpark that couldn't put a football field in in Baltimore.
[SPEAKER_01]: We never had no end zones or no side to anything.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was that small.
[SPEAKER_01]: Pretty tough to pitch in a small park.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, we pitched in it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Earnshaw, Walter, and Tommy Thomas, Jack Onglin.
[SPEAKER_02]: Didn't you kind of feel unhappy that you weren't going up to the Big League?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, no.
[SPEAKER_01]: Why should we feel unhappy when we get paid this much salary?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, there's certain glory and fame in the big time.
[SPEAKER_01]: We ain't crazy.
[SPEAKER_01]: We wasn't like that in them days.
[SPEAKER_01]: We wanted to be up at the Big League, sure.
[SPEAKER_01]: We used to go to Washington.
[SPEAKER_01]: Washington playing Washington in our off days.
[SPEAKER_01]: But it was only 40 miles away from Baltimore.
[SPEAKER_01]: How was Jack Dunn to play for?
[SPEAKER_01]: Great.
[SPEAKER_01]: We had no rules on the ballpark.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's why it was great.
[SPEAKER_01]: We didn't have no certain time to be in a night or anything like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: As long as you walked out in the field and gave them what you had.
[SPEAKER_01]: So it must have worked out pretty good.
[SPEAKER_01]: We won seven pennants.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes sir.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did they have a Little World Series then?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, we started in 20.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's the first Little World Series.
[SPEAKER_02]: How'd you do in that?
[SPEAKER_01]: We beat them.
[SPEAKER_01]: We beat St. Paul.
[SPEAKER_01]: We beat St. Paul in that.
[SPEAKER_02]: Who else was on that Baltimore team?
[SPEAKER_01]: Jack Bentley played first base.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bishop played second, Boley played short, Fritz Schmaderer played third.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was the third baseman?
[SPEAKER_01]: Mazel?
[SPEAKER_01]: Fritz Schmaderer.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was the old third baseman of the Yankees.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bill Holden, Otis Lowry, Merwin Jacobson in the outfield, Ben Higgins, and Dennis Stiles Kessler.
[SPEAKER_01]: Dennis Stiles was up in Philadelphia.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Wahlberg and Earnshaw, you were all together.
[SPEAKER_01]: Wahlberg wasn't there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Earnshaw, Jack Ogden,
[SPEAKER_01]: And Alfonso Thomas, he's a pitcher for the White Sox.
[SPEAKER_02]: A fellow by the name of Harry Frank.
[SPEAKER_02]: A fellow by the name of Clark.
[SPEAKER_02]: How did Dunn get such a good team together?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, he just got together.
[SPEAKER_01]: I couldn't tell you that.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he bought me from Martin for, you know, $3,500.
[SPEAKER_02]: You say you fellas were getting better pay than some of the big leaguers?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, we were getting more money down there than the rent shops were getting.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, we were making $700 a month.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: How about the tenants?
[SPEAKER_02]: Were you drawing?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, we were drawing there.
[SPEAKER_01]: We filled a little ballpark up over there.
[SPEAKER_01]: How big?
[SPEAKER_01]: It wasn't very big, about 8 or 9,000.
[SPEAKER_01]: 8 or 9,000?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was an old wooden ballpark.
[SPEAKER_01]: It burned down pretty late.
[SPEAKER_02]: Is it the site of the...
[SPEAKER_01]: It was on 29th Street and the stadium was on 33rd Street because I lived up past the stadium.
[SPEAKER_01]: I used to have to drive by it every time I went home.
[SPEAKER_01]: East 33rd Street.
[SPEAKER_01]: We all went to the ballpark then.
[SPEAKER_01]: The football stadium.
[SPEAKER_02]: So it was a different field you played on then?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, we had our own ballpark.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was laid out just for football.
[SPEAKER_01]: The ball club took the St. Louis Browns franchise and then they moved everything around to build it different.
[SPEAKER_00]: Let me just check this one.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'll make sure we're coming in here.
[SPEAKER_02]: I missed that part of it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Bentley was sold to the Giants for $75,000.
[SPEAKER_02]: The Grawl wanted you too.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, for $75,000.
[SPEAKER_02]: And Dunn wouldn't sell me for $75,000.
[SPEAKER_02]: So Mr. Mack offered him $100,000, $600,000 for me.
[SPEAKER_02]: So that's the reason I went back.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did Dunn make some decision to break the club up?
[SPEAKER_02]: He seemed to start getting rid of everybody about the same time.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, he lost his son.
[SPEAKER_01]: His son died.
[SPEAKER_01]: He didn't take much interest in the ball club after that.
[SPEAKER_01]: So he just left the work and sold to Bishop.
[SPEAKER_01]: When Bishop came to Philadelphia, Bullard came to Philadelphia with him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did they go up about the same time you did?
[SPEAKER_01]: Bishop did.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bishop and I were together.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then they sent a couple of players from Philadelphia down with them.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bishop was in the deal.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, we had a great ball club down there.
[SPEAKER_02]: There must have been a lot of other clubs after you though, weren't there?
[SPEAKER_02]: Was that record you had of all of them?
[SPEAKER_02]: Other Major League teams that wanted to get you?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh yeah, I guess it was, but I never know.
[SPEAKER_01]: I know that McGraw won them.
[SPEAKER_01]: McGraw and I would have never got along together.
[SPEAKER_02]: How was Connie Mack to play for?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, he was the greatest man in the world.
[SPEAKER_02]: How did he handle his team?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, he handled...everybody at this time was his own son.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, he was a great fella, a great man.
[SPEAKER_01]: When the old man Mack quit and passed away, I sold them all away.
[SPEAKER_01]: There ain't another guy like him.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you ever have any arguments or disputes with him?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, I never had any arguments with Connie.
[SPEAKER_02]: No, we got along very well.
[SPEAKER_02]: In the early days, sometimes I saw your name spelled with an S on the end of it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, well, that didn't make no difference to me.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was that just a mistake?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I didn't do it as a mistake.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's just the way they spelled it, I guess.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's all it was, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: That didn't make the pitch any better.
[SPEAKER_02]: I just was confused whether it was really spelled with an S. No, it was D-R-O-V-E is the way it's supposed to be spelled.
[SPEAKER_01]: Uh-huh.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did they call you Lefty down in the minor leagues?
[SPEAKER_02]: How about high school baseball?
[SPEAKER_01]: Never had none.
[SPEAKER_01]: No high school baseball.
[SPEAKER_02]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you get a chance to pitch much in your teens?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, we played a couple of days a week.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't play from my hometown.
[SPEAKER_01]: They didn't have no clubs.
[SPEAKER_01]: I played from Midland, three miles away.
[SPEAKER_01]: three miles up the road, ride the streetcar, and walk it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Most of the time, walk it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was it a pretty big thrill to be with the athletics?
[SPEAKER_02]: Were you pretty excited to go up the athletics?
[SPEAKER_02]: Or did you just take it in stride?
[SPEAKER_01]: Just took it right in stride.
[SPEAKER_02]: Who were some of the toughest hitters you had now?
[SPEAKER_02]: Say the Yankees of 27 now.
[SPEAKER_01]: They had some good hitters, great hitters.
[SPEAKER_01]: They had some good hitters, they had great hitters.
[SPEAKER_01]: Anybody who walked in that home plate with a bat was tough, if he swung it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Toughest guy of them all.
[SPEAKER_01]: I mean, for, you know, you could give a hit to Joe Soule in Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_01]: He didn't strike out much.
[SPEAKER_01]: He only struck out one year.
[SPEAKER_01]: He struck out three times in one year.
[SPEAKER_01]: So that's how tough he was.
[SPEAKER_01]: He always got in the battle in the ball.
[SPEAKER_02]: How was Ruth?
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't have no trouble with Ruth.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because I beat every ball club out there more games than they beat me.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was ahead of them all.
[SPEAKER_01]: We had good ballplayers.
[SPEAKER_01]: We had pretty good hitters up there.
[SPEAKER_01]: You take the Yankees, you had Ruth, Garrick, Bob Musil, Earl Coombs, and Bill Dickey.
[SPEAKER_01]: Boston only had one hitter that was a center fielder that had Flagstead.
[SPEAKER_01]: St. Louis only had two real hitters, a fellow named Williams and a fellow by the name of George Sisler.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you pitch against Sisler?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh yes.
[SPEAKER_01]: How was he?
[SPEAKER_01]: I said he was a good hitter.
[SPEAKER_01]: Caldwell had Mossel and Bibb Falk.
[SPEAKER_01]: They were pretty good hitters.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about Cleveland?
[SPEAKER_00]: My favorite team.
[SPEAKER_01]: I forget who they were.
[SPEAKER_01]: They had Boswick and Trotsky.
[SPEAKER_01]: They had Dick Porter over there.
[SPEAKER_02]: I saw you beat them a number of times out there.
[SPEAKER_02]: They didn't give you much trouble as I recall.
[SPEAKER_02]: That little ballpark too.
[SPEAKER_02]: How was it pitching where you had a short fence like League Park or Yankee Stadium?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, you just pitch away all the time.
[SPEAKER_01]: You just pitch away, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, you pitch like you're a left-hand hitter so you just pitch it outside all the time.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you have any favorite parks you liked to pitch in at all?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, I didn't.
[SPEAKER_01]: I guess Chicago was the best ballpark and mall to pitch in.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was bigger than it is now.
[SPEAKER_01]: They fenced the center field out of Chicago now.
[SPEAKER_01]: We didn't have that.
[SPEAKER_01]: The Yankees was a good ballpark to pitch in.
[SPEAKER_01]: Boston was a short left field fence.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, our ballpark in Philadelphia was only about 330 feet down each foul line.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did they have a high fence at first?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, the fence, they had a concrete fence about 12 feet high at first.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then they built a big steel fence.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, that was after I even quit there.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, after I left there, they put a new fence up on top of the steel.
[SPEAKER_01]: So the people on them houses across the street couldn't see in.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, heck, we only could get in about a block.
[SPEAKER_01]: thirty-two, thirty-three thousand and put us out there.
[SPEAKER_02]: I never was in a game.
[SPEAKER_01]: Actually, he kind of broke up the ball club because he, I mean, he could have drawn up money.
[SPEAKER_01]: People didn't, well, we'd draw good, but he was paying big salaries, and they just couldn't.
[SPEAKER_01]: Actually, he had to break them up.
[SPEAKER_01]: That was a tremendous team.
[SPEAKER_01]: Boy.
[SPEAKER_00]: He really was hard-pressed for funds.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's why he broke that team up.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, we won the World Series, we won the Penn, the World Series in twenty-nine.
[SPEAKER_01]: In 31 we lost, I forget how many hundred thousand people.
[SPEAKER_01]: We lost 30.
[SPEAKER_01]: In 31 we lost more.
[SPEAKER_01]: We won the peasant 30.
[SPEAKER_01]: In 31 we still didn't... Lost money?
[SPEAKER_01]: We lost money.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_01]: Of course the depression years were pretty bad.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, it was the depression.
[SPEAKER_01]: Simmons was getting about $33,000 a year in that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Myself and Ernst Shaw.
[SPEAKER_01]: You were getting over $30,000?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, we didn't get that much.
[SPEAKER_01]: Simmons was the highest payer on the mall.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you have any contract arguments with Connie Meyer?
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: He sent a contract, he didn't like it, just wrote back telling him he didn't like it, and that was it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Held out one year, not very long.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did he handle all the contracts on you?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a general manager and manager, I guess.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yep, he was everything.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a great old man.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yes, sir.
[SPEAKER_02]: Where did you live while you were with the Philadelphia team?
[SPEAKER_02]: In Philadelphia.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you own property there?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: I came back home in the wintertime.
[SPEAKER_01]: The last season was over.
[SPEAKER_01]: To Lone Oconee?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yep.
[SPEAKER_02]: What did you do there in the winters?
[SPEAKER_02]: Nothing.
[SPEAKER_02]: Hunt fish.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you own a... Bowl Valley.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was that during your playing days or was that later?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: I built it in there in about 29.
[SPEAKER_02]: Were you married while you were at Baltimore?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yep.
[SPEAKER_02]: When did you get married?
[SPEAKER_02]: 1920, 1921.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was your wife from hometown?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: She only lived a half block from me.
[SPEAKER_02]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did she travel with you much?
[SPEAKER_02]: Not on the road.
[SPEAKER_01]: I mean, I was in spring training and during the World Series she'd go.
[SPEAKER_01]: I took the trip to Japan and she wanted to go with us.
[SPEAKER_01]: Fred Lee handled that, didn't he?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: We have a group of baseball historians and researchers which had a meeting in Philadelphia just about a month ago and Fred Lee
[SPEAKER_02]: He's an old boy.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, his sister lives in Haverford.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was there.
[SPEAKER_02]: He came to talk to us.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's 86 now.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, he's pretty old.
[SPEAKER_02]: But he's in good shape.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's a little thin guy in this game.
[SPEAKER_02]: Great baseball writer.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, he doesn't know about baseball.
[SPEAKER_01]: He goes, he's up in Cooperstown every year.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, he knows a lot of baseball.
[SPEAKER_02]: Does your wife like baseball?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, she does, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: She go out to the games all the time?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, every day.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did she, uh...
[SPEAKER_02]: No, she never says nothing.
[SPEAKER_02]: No, she's just there.
[SPEAKER_02]: You get nervous when you're pitching?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, no.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know why she'd need to be.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you ever get knocked out of the box very often?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I couldn't.
[SPEAKER_01]: You ask me questions I can't answer.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_01]: See, I wouldn't know how much or how many times.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I'm just trying to think of how it would be handled by Connie Mack.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, you just send them back.
[SPEAKER_01]: See, Connie never wore a uniform.
[SPEAKER_01]: She sent his coach out.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's a different rule now.
[SPEAKER_01]: I mean, back in the day, you'd go up the hill, go up the mountain, off if you wanted.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, you're going to do it a second time out, you automatically have the pitchers out.
[SPEAKER_01]: We still played the games faster than we did in the day.
[SPEAKER_02]: Most pitchers finish the games, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, well, we only had seven or eight pitchers.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now we've got ten or eleven.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's all really pitching now, mostly.
[SPEAKER_01]: They have a lot of good ball players, heck of a lot of good ball players, but they've got different equipment than we had.
[SPEAKER_01]: The guns and everything is a lot different, the fields are different, there are diamonds, there are pool tables, we are a little rough.
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you still have much interest in the game?
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you watch it or read about it?
[SPEAKER_01]: I go to Cleveland and when I saw Perry pitch his 14th straight, I think it was his 14th, 14th straight.
[SPEAKER_02]: On a Friday rain, I think.
[SPEAKER_02]: Were you pretty interested in this effort of his to tie your record?
[SPEAKER_01]: I was pulling for him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you hear that game that night?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: That was a heartbreaker.
[SPEAKER_01]: He pitches at night.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's a great pitcher.
[SPEAKER_02]: What about this pitball business?
[SPEAKER_02]: Was there much of that in your time?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, we had pitball pitchers in there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Jack Quinn, Ben Faber.
[SPEAKER_01]: Those that pitched before the band, but I mean afterwards.
[SPEAKER_01]: Any illegal pitching?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, there was no illegal, but some of them thought of it.
[SPEAKER_02]: What was that great year you had, 31?
[SPEAKER_02]: 1931, you won 31, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: That must have been quite a year.
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you remember much about that year?
[SPEAKER_01]: Not so much, no.
[SPEAKER_01]: Pitching my regular turn every fourth day, three days rest.
[SPEAKER_02]: You led the league, you earned run average, too.
[SPEAKER_02]: I mean, you lost your run average, so it must have been
[SPEAKER_02]: You had great hitting support, but you had great pitching, too.
[SPEAKER_02]: How about your defense behind you?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, we had good, pretty good defense.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, at first, when I went up, it wasn't so good.
[SPEAKER_02]: I mean, I went up in 25. Who was the first baseman then?
[SPEAKER_02]: Fox wasn't up yet, was he?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, Fox comes up as a catcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: J.O.
[SPEAKER_01]: Joe Hauser.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, he broke his kneecap.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then Bishop was there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Mowley was.
[SPEAKER_01]: We found a guy named Chick Galloway at the shortstop.
[SPEAKER_01]: Jimmy Dykes III, yeah, Jimmy was there.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was the third baseman in Jimmy Dykes.
[SPEAKER_01]: There was a guy I think ought to be in the Hall of Fame.
[SPEAKER_01]: With his record, I mean, he was a record.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, Bing was an outfielder.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bing Miller and Mule Hatch and Roger Cramer and Al Simmons.
[SPEAKER_01]: But Mule Hatch just died.
[SPEAKER_01]: A couple of weeks ago I know.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you fellas get together much in your retirement days at all?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, we used to get together once in a while.
[SPEAKER_01]: We'd come and have some of these old-timers fill it up.
[SPEAKER_01]: I haven't saw Earnshaw for a long while.
[SPEAKER_01]: Since the last time we filled it up.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's in Arkansas somewhere.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a great right-hand pitcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is Wahlberg still around?
[SPEAKER_01]: He's down in Miami.
[SPEAKER_01]: Some of the overseas managers of the golf course are down in Miami.
[SPEAKER_02]: Remember that 1929 World Series when Donnie Mack starred Howard Emke?
[SPEAKER_02]: That was a great surprise to everybody.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was that a surprise to you fellows?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, it was.
[SPEAKER_01]: We didn't know until that morning who was going to pitch, him or I.
[SPEAKER_01]: They said, well, the Cubs would murder the left-handers, but us left-handers, Wahlberg and I, have to do all the relief work.
[SPEAKER_01]: We did.
[SPEAKER_01]: Earnshaw started the second game, and I relieved him.
[SPEAKER_01]: The second game, it was the Cubs.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I didn't get no credit for it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Earnshaw got credit for the game, and I relieved him.
[SPEAKER_02]: But that was a pretty good choice, I guess, Emke.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had a great game.
[SPEAKER_02]: He pulled one out of the hat there.
[SPEAKER_02]: I guess he's pretty old then, but he had quite a career after all that.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, he did.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, we had a great ballclub going sometimes.
[SPEAKER_02]: How did you learn that you were going to be traded to Boston?
[SPEAKER_02]: In 1933, I guess.
[SPEAKER_02]: Winter of 1933.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: He called and told me.
[SPEAKER_02]: Tony Mack called you?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: You were at home and he just... Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: What did he say?
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you remember?
[SPEAKER_01]: He just said that we were trading you, selling you, selling you to Boston for $125,000.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's like that's all he said.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you expect this?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, I didn't expect anything in baseball.
Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: We would, cities didn't mean nothing to us.
[SPEAKER_01]: Wherever we played, we had to play.
[SPEAKER_01]: We were in a cage, that's all that mattered.
[SPEAKER_01]: We wouldn't pick our cities where we wanted to go or anywhere.
[SPEAKER_02]: Then, your first year in Boston, you...
[SPEAKER_02]: I had a sore arm.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_02]: You never had one of those before, did you?
[SPEAKER_02]: Nope.
[SPEAKER_02]: How'd that develop?
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know what happened to it.
[SPEAKER_01]: It just came up sore.
[SPEAKER_01]: and swim up Soarer Spring Train.
[SPEAKER_02]: Almost seems surprising.
[SPEAKER_02]: You'd be traded, get the Soarer Armistice, and you're traded, isn't it?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: But then you had a good year after that.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, I won 20 the next year, 35. Who was managing Boston then when you went over?
[SPEAKER_02]: Bucky Harris.
[SPEAKER_02]: That wasn't a very strong team, was it?
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think we finished fifth.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did Jimmy Fox come over a little later?
[SPEAKER_01]: Fox came in about 35 again.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yawkey bought the team, I guess, in 33, didn't he?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: 32, I think.
[SPEAKER_00]: 32 or 33.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then he began buying some of the players, couldn't he?
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a great man too, boy, I'll tell you that.
[SPEAKER_02]: He didn't swirl up in Boston.
[SPEAKER_02]: He didn't, he wasn't in Boston much though, was he?
[SPEAKER_02]: He didn't live there, did he?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, we lived in New York.
[SPEAKER_01]: He knew what was going on all the time.
[SPEAKER_01]: How was Bucky Harris to play for?
[SPEAKER_01]: Bucky was great.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bucky was a great man.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then Crowley, they got Crowley, and Joe was there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, Joe was all right.
[SPEAKER_01]: Joe was very good.
[SPEAKER_01]: Good baseball.
[SPEAKER_01]: I liked Joe very much.
[SPEAKER_02]: You had some good managers, didn't you?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yep.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, we had Joe McCarthy one time, for one year.
[SPEAKER_02]: Must have been towards...
[SPEAKER_01]: When would that have been?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, that's, I think...
[SPEAKER_01]: I forget what year that was.
[SPEAKER_01]: McCarthy came there.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was only there for one year.
[SPEAKER_02]: At Boston, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: I think he, uh, he, uh, Bucky Harrison and I think Joe McCartney came in and Cronin took it.
[SPEAKER_01]: The operative was Cronin and then from Washington.
[SPEAKER_02]: How about that 300th game?
[SPEAKER_02]: It was kind of... Well, he tried to win it.
[SPEAKER_02]: How did, how did, what kind of a game was it?
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you remember it much?
[SPEAKER_02]: I beat Cleveland 10-5 in Boston.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you pitch the whole game?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: You were over 40 years old then, weren't you?
[SPEAKER_02]: 41.
[SPEAKER_02]: That was right at the end of the season, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, that was in September, July, August, September.
[SPEAKER_02]: If you hadn't gotten it then, do you think you would have tried it?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I was that close I was going to try it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Seems to me if you'd have come up earlier, you'd have had it so much easier.
[SPEAKER_02]: You'd have probably gotten 400.
[SPEAKER_01]: We didn't get up early.
[SPEAKER_01]: I went up there about 22-wise in three more years.
[SPEAKER_01]: I've pitched 17 years up there.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was down where we are.
[SPEAKER_02]: We got the Cincinnati games.
[SPEAKER_02]: And Cincinnati played St. Louis last night.
[SPEAKER_02]: Gibson pitched for St. Louis.
[SPEAKER_02]: He got a 3,000 strikeout.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, he only had a few to go.
[SPEAKER_02]: I know.
[SPEAKER_02]: I see you have 2266 here.
[SPEAKER_02]: Again, if you'd have been up.
[SPEAKER_02]: I had three years on that.
[SPEAKER_02]: Because I guess Walter Johnson is the only other player to have 3,000 strikeouts.
[SPEAKER_02]: Walter Johnson has 3,508.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's a pretty good record.
[SPEAKER_02]: Great pitcher.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you ever see him?
[SPEAKER_02]: I guess you saw him.
[SPEAKER_02]: I pitched against him.
[SPEAKER_01]: I opened a 1925 season up against him in Philadelphia.
[SPEAKER_01]: He beat me 4-2.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a long years by that time wasn't he?
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know why I was picked that day.
[SPEAKER_01]: I mean a rookie just coming in, a young guy.
[SPEAKER_01]: So they put me in an open season up in Philadelphia.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, Walter, we used to go and see him pitch when I was playing in Baltimore.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was that right?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Where you go and see Cobb and all them guys.
[SPEAKER_01]: You pitched against Cobb, didn't you?
[SPEAKER_01]: Cobb, Speaker, Sistler, Allman, Root, Garrick.
[SPEAKER_01]: How was Cobb?
[SPEAKER_01]: Cobb was a pretty tough hitter.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a smart hitter.
[SPEAKER_01]: He played with us in 28.
[SPEAKER_01]: So did Speaker.
[SPEAKER_02]: Zach Wheat.
[SPEAKER_02]: Some outfielders, they've been in their prime, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, boy.
[SPEAKER_02]: Harry Heilman seems to me to be a great hitter.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's a great hitter.
[SPEAKER_02]: He never has been recognized very much.
[SPEAKER_02]: No, I mean, boy, he's a good outfielder, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's a long winner.
[SPEAKER_01]: I mean, he wasn't just hitting.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's a good outfielder.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, another fellow there was a pretty good outfielder, too, one time.
[SPEAKER_02]: Bob Farger.
[SPEAKER_02]: Bob Farger, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Big fat guy.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, fatty fat guy.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: I guess he may have been too fat for a long career, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, I guess so.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's an Ohio boy.
[SPEAKER_00]: He came from where our mansion was.
Well, uh...
[SPEAKER_02]: Have any big thrills that stick out in your mind?
[SPEAKER_02]: Every day is a thrill.
[SPEAKER_02]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah boy.
[SPEAKER_02]: I love to play ball.
[SPEAKER_02]: Must make you wonder about some of these modern ball players.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: I've been out of there for 33 years.
[SPEAKER_01]: Got some of these kids, one of them was born 33 years ago.
[SPEAKER_01]: See, we had a lot of minor leagues in those days.
[SPEAKER_01]: We had a lot of minor league clubs.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, the big leagues own most all the minor league clubs.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I guess we only got AAA now, and AAA, AAA, and the rest.
[SPEAKER_01]: See, there used to be AA then, but they went to AAA.
[SPEAKER_01]: with double A and A and B and C and D. You had all the B's, C's and D's out of there.
[SPEAKER_01]: What was Martinsburg, the Blue Ridge League, what was it?
[SPEAKER_01]: C?
[SPEAKER_01]: C, I think it was.
[SPEAKER_01]: That was a good league, Hagerstown in there, Frederick, Hanover.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you ever meet Ban Johnson?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh yeah, he was the president of the American League when I went out.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you ever meet him?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, Chicago.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you tell me about that?
[SPEAKER_02]: Because I'm doing a little research on bandages.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I just met him, that's all.
[SPEAKER_01]: Where were you, in the office or at the ballpark?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, I was in the hotel.
[SPEAKER_01]: Judge lined us.
[SPEAKER_01]: Judges used to come down to the hotel and visit the ball club.
[SPEAKER_01]: He visited us all the time.
[SPEAKER_01]: Why didn't he come and visit Mr. Mack and any of his players?
[SPEAKER_01]: You just exchanged pleasantries to Ben.
[SPEAKER_01]: You didn't get a chance to talk to him, I understand.
[SPEAKER_02]: That was a pretty nice chapter.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, we should have a commissioner like Lance now.
[SPEAKER_01]: It'd be a little different, I believe.
[SPEAKER_02]: Maybe that's why they don't have one like Lenny's.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was so tough.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was really a great baseball commissioner.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think some of the owners thought he was a little too severe.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, they always put him back in the office.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, I know they did.
[SPEAKER_02]: There wasn't a whole lot of them.
[SPEAKER_02]: But they never put another one like him in since his time.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, there wasn't no other one like him.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think they want to control the commissioner, don't you think?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't believe that.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, I don't believe that.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's different altogether.
[SPEAKER_01]: Altogether.
[SPEAKER_01]: Everything's different.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, it's everything.
[SPEAKER_01]: There's a lot of difference.
[SPEAKER_01]: All parts of difference.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's everything.
[SPEAKER_01]: And there's some great ballplayers up there.
[SPEAKER_01]: You know, they're all young and they look like they can go for a year, quite a few years, you know.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, you said how you just love to play ball, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, I used to play ball neat.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, man.
[SPEAKER_01]: There was a ballpark every morning, early around 9 o'clock in the morning, and we didn't play until 3 o'clock in the afternoon.
[SPEAKER_01]: Never started a doubleheader at 2 o'clock.
[SPEAKER_01]: We had no lights to turn on.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now they turn the lights on at 3 o'clock in the afternoon.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you ever pitch night ball?
[SPEAKER_01]: Nope, never pitched a game at night.
[SPEAKER_01]: I wonder what effect that had.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, in my latter couple of years, they had me put in Lake Moline, and Chicago, and Philadelphia, and Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_01]: So they didn't bother.
[SPEAKER_01]: We left with this thing.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I wasn't real fast then.
[SPEAKER_02]: I mean, it was the tail end of my career.
[SPEAKER_02]: You say your fastball left you, or you weren't as fast?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I don't know now, what year.
[SPEAKER_01]: I can't take the year out.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's a gradual process.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had a good curveball then.
[SPEAKER_01]: I developed a good curveball and a good fartball.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you have a curveball earlier?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, of course, about five or six years after I got there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did anybody teach you that?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, we had no pitcher coaches.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did other pitchers help you when you come up at all?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, we were on our own.
[SPEAKER_01]: We only had two coaches.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who were they?
[SPEAKER_01]: Eddie Collins and Kit Gleason.
[SPEAKER_02]: Gleason knows baseball pretty well.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's the old Chicago manager.
[SPEAKER_01]: That really broke him up until 1919.
[SPEAKER_01]: He managed that.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did he ever talk much about that?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: We never mentioned it to him.
[SPEAKER_01]: We know how much it hurt him and we never bothered him.
[SPEAKER_02]: Of course, Eddie Collins was on that team too.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, Collins.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did he ever say much?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: We never asked no questions about it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Too sensitive, wasn't he?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yep.
[SPEAKER_01]: We didn't want to bother him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bring back memories like that stuff to him.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was there ever much feeling about you fellows about kicking those guys out?
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you ever think much about it?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, never thought about it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Never thought about it.
[SPEAKER_02]: When you played in Cleveland, where did the team stay?
[SPEAKER_02]: It was the old Holland Hotel.
[SPEAKER_01]: I see.
[SPEAKER_01]: We didn't stay at the Cleveland Hotel until I went to Boston, then they moved to the Cleveland Hotel.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's when they moved down the stadium, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, well, uh... Yeah, I pitched the first game when I was a little out of it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, you pitched against Bill Harder that day.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was at Philadelphia.
[SPEAKER_01]: We used to haul around the hotel there.
[SPEAKER_02]: What was that?
[SPEAKER_02]: That must have been a big thrill, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, it was.
[SPEAKER_01]: We would pitch the open stadium, just like opening the open game.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, a lot of people thought that was a great event.
[SPEAKER_02]: Cleveland's home run output was cut in half when they moved down the stadium.
[SPEAKER_02]: They couldn't hit the ball out of that part.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, we didn't have, there was no fence like you got out there.
[SPEAKER_01]: You hit one between the outfields and drove it over miles.
[SPEAKER_02]: April, I think, had 32 home runs before then, about 10 after that.
[SPEAKER_02]: His triple output went up just the other way.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, sure.
[SPEAKER_01]: In between the fielder, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, it rolled about right center and left center.
[SPEAKER_01]: It rolled just like Yankee Stadium was.
[SPEAKER_01]: I guess the Yankees, their stadium would be a different ballpark altogether after you get remodeled.
[SPEAKER_01]: I guess you're tearing everything out of there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yep.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is it needed?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, imagine that it was in there since when, 22?
[SPEAKER_01]: It won't hold as many people, I don't think.
[SPEAKER_02]: I guess not.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't like these new parks.
[SPEAKER_02]: They don't strike me as baseball parks.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, one of these new ones they built, they're a regulated park.
[SPEAKER_01]: Both foul lines are built the same, same space all the way.
[SPEAKER_01]: The only thing I don't like about it is that acid turf.
[SPEAKER_01]: Boy, that's hot in the feet.
[SPEAKER_01]: But we were going to St. Louis and that.
[SPEAKER_01]: You know, standing, standing ought to be an introduction.
[SPEAKER_01]: Old-timers, eh?
[SPEAKER_01]: You feel the heat.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: And it's changed defensive play, too, the way...
[SPEAKER_02]: The ball really takes off on that.
[SPEAKER_02]: I see the ball bounce over the field a bit.
[SPEAKER_02]: So, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'll stick with the old Mother Earth play.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't like taking away the dirt infield either, they've got that carpeted too.
[SPEAKER_01]: It doesn't look like a ballpark, it looks like a living room.
[SPEAKER_01]: All that green all around, all the places, dirt is around the bases.
[SPEAKER_02]: What ballpark do you play in at the best facilities, that is, shower, locker, are they all pretty much the same, or any that stand out at all?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, let's see.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yankee was pretty good.
[SPEAKER_01]: Irish and Boston was good.
[SPEAKER_01]: St. Louis was lousy.
[SPEAKER_01]: Washington was lousy.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was lousy.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about Link Park in Cleveland?
[SPEAKER_01]: It was lousy too.
[SPEAKER_01]: Terrible, terrible.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you ever play in Baker Bowl at all?
[SPEAKER_02]: Exhibition games?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, exhibition games.
[SPEAKER_01]: We played the Phillies in the spring of the year.
[SPEAKER_01]: That would have been some strange ballpark, wouldn't it?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, it got us scared to death.
[SPEAKER_01]: We weren't even walking on it.
[SPEAKER_01]: We'd get into the bench.
[SPEAKER_01]: We could go fall in.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was all wood.
[SPEAKER_02]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, you got them timbered up and underneath and everything.
[SPEAKER_01]: Miracle never fell in.
[SPEAKER_01]: Boy, that was a terrible ballpark.
[SPEAKER_01]: See, we dressed our own ballpark.
[SPEAKER_01]: We had to go down and get in cabs.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, I see you didn't take a chance down there, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, you never dressed down there.
[SPEAKER_02]: They did have a dressing room, though.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yes, they did.
[SPEAKER_01]: Sure, they always had a dressing room down there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Centerfield.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_01]: Like the Giants used to do in Centerfield.
[SPEAKER_02]: I guess that right field fence in Baker Bowl was kind of close.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, right fielder, he had the extra second baseman.
[SPEAKER_01]: Boom, boom, back, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, that tin fence?
[SPEAKER_02]: That's pretty good ballplayers over there, Earl.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did Chuck Kline hit all the home runs at any other park, you think?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, Chuck was a good hitter.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a strong hitter.
[SPEAKER_02]: He got a little bit of help there, though.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, sure.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did, uh...
[SPEAKER_02]: Well Dizzy Dean wasn't pitching for the Cardinals in the World Series, was he?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, he wasn't up there.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's 34 and 35, that's against Detroit.
[SPEAKER_01]: He went up in 32, didn't he?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, I think so.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think it was about 32 he went up.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you know him very well?
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't diss very well, that's for good.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's sort of backwards.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's crazy as he sounds.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, he's just as crazy as he was.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's a great guy.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, he's a great guy.
[SPEAKER_01]: I never met his brother, Paul.
[SPEAKER_01]: Had he been ill before his death here, do you know?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't hear anything about it.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't either.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was playing golf with another capo.
[SPEAKER_02]: You've been in a hospital a day or two before, but I guess that was something that just developed there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you recall any really amusing or funny things that happened while you were playing ball?
[SPEAKER_02]: So many things happened, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, you know, we just knew they were along and never paid much attention to it anyway.
[SPEAKER_01]: I mean, we didn't bother.
[SPEAKER_01]: We'd play ball in the back of the hotel or the back of the home or apartment and eat dinner.
[SPEAKER_02]: What would you do in the evenings or off hours?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, once in a while you could see pretty good movies.
[SPEAKER_01]: We used to go to the movies on the road.
[SPEAKER_01]: Card playing?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, we played a lot of cards.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, we played a lot of cards.
[SPEAKER_01]: Long train trips, a lot of... Oh boy, yeah, what are you talking about train trips?
[SPEAKER_01]: Killed some of these guys today on that train trip.
[SPEAKER_01]: Leave Boston at 5 o'clock at night and then don't get to St. Louis until the next night at 5.
[SPEAKER_01]: 6 o'clock, St. Louis time.
[SPEAKER_01]: And no air conditioning.
[SPEAKER_01]: Middle of July.
[SPEAKER_01]: We played cards.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, what would you do to kill the time?
[SPEAKER_02]: You couldn't play cards?
[SPEAKER_01]: Get on the train.
[SPEAKER_01]: Just sit there, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: You had your own sleeper, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you sleep much on those things?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, I slept pretty good on them.
[SPEAKER_02]: Hot as they were?
[SPEAKER_02]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: Pretty hot, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, sure, it'd be hot as hell.
[SPEAKER_01]: You'd sleep all right.
[SPEAKER_01]: Once you get to sleep, there wasn't no hotter on the train than there was sleeping in the hotel in St. Louis.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was 118 degrees in there, 15.
[SPEAKER_01]: We fried an egg on the pavement.
[SPEAKER_02]: A lot of horseplay in that great Philadelphia team, among the players?
[SPEAKER_02]: Are they all pretty serious?
[SPEAKER_02]: Were there any jokesters?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, well, they played a lot of jokes.
[SPEAKER_01]: Jimmy Dykes was a jokester.
[SPEAKER_01]: There was a happy family.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's what it was.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was just one big happy family.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, we'd start our ball game at three o'clock in the afternoon.
[SPEAKER_01]: Six o'clock, we was eating our dinner.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was an hour and a half, two hours.
[SPEAKER_02]: You'd be back home and eating at home?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Or did you run an apartment in Philadelphia?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, I ran a home.
[SPEAKER_02]: Just you and your wife or a couple of the players?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, myself and my wife and my two children.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then the same in Boston.
[SPEAKER_01]: I ran an apartment in Boston.
[SPEAKER_01]: Children, I never took them out of school.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was the only player in Maryland in school.
[SPEAKER_01]: I wouldn't change school.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Mr. would stay with him until the school was out and they'd all come live with me then.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: My boy passed away about three years, two years ago.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's an engineer for Ford Motor Company.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did he play much ball?
[SPEAKER_02]: He played a little up there in New England.
[SPEAKER_02]: Professionally though?
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_02]: How did he happen to come here?
[SPEAKER_02]: Is this the Ford Company?
[SPEAKER_01]: He was, I don't know, he used to work for the Kelly Springfield Tire Company and come out this way with Kelly Tire Sales, Kelly Tire Sales.
[SPEAKER_01]: Dealers.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then he got a job out here, he got a place out here with the Ford Motor Company over in San Diego, Indiana.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a supervisor of engineering and packaging in Connersville, Indiana.
[SPEAKER_02]: So you came here then?
[SPEAKER_02]: After my missus passed away.
[SPEAKER_02]: When was that?
[SPEAKER_02]: I've been here since 1961.
[SPEAKER_02]: I see.
[SPEAKER_02]: You'd been in Lonokone?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's where you lived after your baseball days?
[SPEAKER_02]: That's where I went backstage.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you run the bowling alley then?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well...
[SPEAKER_00]: This interview was on Thursday, July 18, 1974.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had to attend a meeting in Delaware at Ohio Western at the Ohio Athletic Conference at 2 o'clock in the afternoon on the problem of women's athletics.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I figured this would be a chance to work in a trip to Norwalk and see Lefty Grove.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I left about quarter to 7 in the morning and got up to Norwalk around 10, 15.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had called him on last Sunday evening.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he said, I might be up.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he said, well, give him a call when I get up there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he would know better then if he could talk to me well.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I didn't know I was going to have an interview.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I got up there and got into town, as I say, a little bit after 10, stopped into an Allen K restaurant to make the phone call.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he wasn't home.
[SPEAKER_00]: I talked to his daughter-in-law, who was bedridden.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she said, he'd be home by 11.
[SPEAKER_00]: Why didn't I come out then?
[SPEAKER_00]: So that gave me a little time to eat, since I wasn't likely to have much time to eat after the interview on my way down to Delaware.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I ate, and I went out there.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got there around 11, and I had a little trouble finding the place, but not too much.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was on the northeast end of town in Norwalk.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I went up and rang the bell, and the bell didn't work, so I knocked on it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Some guy's painting the house in front.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said the bell didn't work, so I rapped on the door.
[SPEAKER_00]: This old lady, an elderly woman, must have been in her late 50s, who was the housekeeper, came and let me in.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she called Mr. Grove.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he was down in the basement.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's a pretty hot day, and he's down in the basement, recreation and watching TV in the dark and gloom there.
[SPEAKER_00]: So he came up pretty soon.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a great big guy, stood there almost
[SPEAKER_00]: like he was challenging me.
[SPEAKER_00]: He came in the room and stood stiff and stern and said, hello or yes or something like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't make any effort to come over to shake my hand at all.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I made the first move.
[SPEAKER_00]: I smiled ingratiatingly and walked over and introduced myself and shook hands.
[SPEAKER_00]: He then shook hands and I explained to him who I was and he knew and I said what I was there for and he remembered.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, yack him on down.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I didn't have my tape recorder briefcase, so I went back out and got it and came on down into his basement recreation room, as they say.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's a darkened room there with a television going.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was just down there watching television, I guess.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's a house in a rather nice, rather newly developed area, a small house, which, as you can tell from the tape, was his son's house.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he moved there to live with them when his wife died in 1961.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the son himself is deceased, and the daughter-in-law is bettered, and I did not meet her.
[SPEAKER_00]: She was in bed, and he made no effort to introduce me, so I didn't press, and I was getting rushed for time and a half.
[SPEAKER_00]: This was Lefty Grove, still a tall, handsome man, about 6'3 or so.
[SPEAKER_00]: Had a little stomach on him, but not too much.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was in that shock of handsome gray hair, was still there, hadn't lost any of his hair.
[SPEAKER_00]: His face is well-shaped, somewhat thin and wrinkled as the years have taken their toll, but he's still a pretty handsome guy.
[SPEAKER_00]: This mighty left arm of his didn't seem very big or heavy or strong.
[SPEAKER_00]: Both arms seemed rather slim.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had some advantage in getting fast pitch and whiplash at that pitch.
[SPEAKER_00]: This was one of the hardest interviews I ever had to do.
[SPEAKER_00]: As you could tell, I was kind of
[SPEAKER_00]: strained all the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had a speech impediment.
[SPEAKER_00]: He wasn't very friendly.
[SPEAKER_00]: As I was leaving there, after we all got through, I went out, I asked him for some pictures, so we went out in the back and took a couple of his, of him, unsmilingly.
[SPEAKER_00]: But as we walked away, he began to smile a little bit.
[SPEAKER_00]: I showed my appreciation.
[SPEAKER_00]: How proud I was to meet him and talk with him.
[SPEAKER_00]: He began to warm up a little bit.
[SPEAKER_00]: Maybe if I would see him again, it would be a lot easier.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he didn't volunteer too much.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't have too much to say.
[SPEAKER_00]: Some of the great thrills of his lifetime didn't seem to be great thrills at all to him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Nothing seemed to excite him very much.
[SPEAKER_00]: He took things pretty much in his stride.
[SPEAKER_00]: Without any sense of humor,
[SPEAKER_00]: So this was not an easy interview.
[SPEAKER_00]: I suppose I felt the pressure of time a little bit.
[SPEAKER_00]: We didn't get going at 11 o'clock.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had to be in Delaware at 2, and I was wondering if I was going to make it, and I didn't know just how long it would take to get down there.
[SPEAKER_00]: As it turned out, I got there a little bit late.
[SPEAKER_00]: It wasn't too bad, though.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I could see right away that it was going to be a much shorter interview than I thought.
[SPEAKER_00]: It might be an hour and a half in the hour.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I figured if I got 45 minutes, one side of the tape would be a kind of remarkable thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: The lady just didn't have much to say.
[SPEAKER_00]: And although I had his record right there, I had a daguerreotypes.
[SPEAKER_00]: and had Oliver just hit a triple once in the game, Al Oliver.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I had a Gary Otay's record right there, and I had that to work with.
[SPEAKER_00]: But when somebody's like this, doesn't have much to say, doesn't remember any interesting incidents or any unusual anecdotes, it kind of
[SPEAKER_00]: It slows down your question-developing process.
[SPEAKER_00]: I thought I'd be able to ask plenty of questions, but I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: I seemed to run out of gas there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Good leading questions, which normally would open things up, just didn't get anywhere.
[SPEAKER_00]: They didn't open up at all.
[SPEAKER_00]: So it was a little disappointing, but I did have a 45-minute interview, and I spent about an hour with them.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I figure I got out of him perhaps as much as I could have.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I did talk to him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Sorry I didn't get more, but I did get something.
[SPEAKER_00]: I learned something about the man.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I suppose that made it worthwhile.
[SPEAKER_00]: We went out afterwards in the back, and as I say, I took a couple pictures of him in his T-shirt.
[SPEAKER_00]: It wasn't exactly a soiled t-shirt, but it wasn't a clean one either.
[SPEAKER_00]: And a pair of kind of work pants on.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I took a couple pictures under the tree.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then I bid goodbye and left.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was about noon or shortly thereafter.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got down a block away off of Parsons on to St. Mary Street and was heading back into town.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I remembered I had a couple of pictures I'd taken along from the autograph, and I'd forgotten to get them out of there.
[SPEAKER_00]: He so quashed my enthusiasm, I didn't even think of that.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I did.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went back then.
[SPEAKER_00]: I thought I'd better get the autographs.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I got the pictures.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went, parked, went up the door, and rang the bell.
[SPEAKER_00]: It didn't ring again.
[SPEAKER_00]: I panicked, said it didn't ring, and I knocked on the door.
[SPEAKER_00]: house mother came along and she sent me down where he was watching TV in the dark then.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I forgot the autograph, so he was very nice about it, signed two pictures I had and gave me a Hall of Fame little card which he had autographed, much like the one, in fact, identical with the one Stanley Kowalewski gave me.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I thanked him again and took off.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he wished me well.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was, I suppose, quite nice, as nice as he is to anybody.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I was just sorry I didn't have more on that tape.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, to follow me the rest of the day, I left Norwalk about quarter after twelve, then, after the second visit to the house.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it was getting awfully hot, and the air conditioning in the car didn't work very well.
[SPEAKER_00]: A little bit worse, I suppose, without it, but it was pretty hot in that car.
[SPEAKER_00]: The sun was beating right down on me through the windows, and when the air conditioner's on, the sun's on, and it nullifies what the air conditioning does.
[SPEAKER_00]: I took Route 61, was it, out south of Norwalk, which went for a while, then ran into 598, and I went through Galleon,
[SPEAKER_00]: And then I hit another route there, 309, took me over to Marion.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't have to go through these towns, there were bypasses.
[SPEAKER_00]: I hit Route 23 outside Marion and got down to Delaware, and went right to the university, and I found the Smith Hall, which is a co-educational dormitory where we had our meeting.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I got there about a little after 2.
[SPEAKER_00]: I freshened up, I was hot and perspiring, and I found I'd burned a hole in my
[SPEAKER_00]: I guess I did that later.
[SPEAKER_00]: I burned a hole in a nice new shirt I was wearing.
[SPEAKER_00]: A cigar actually was cut down.
[SPEAKER_00]: Anyhow, it was kind of decrepit, so I washed up and freshened up and went to a meeting there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And this was the special meeting on the status of women's intercollegiate athletics in the Ohio Conference.
[SPEAKER_00]: We met for about two hours in session and some socializing and other informal business afterwards.
[SPEAKER_00]: The main thing we did was to repeal the mail rule in the Ohio Conference bylaws, which says only bona fide mail undergraduate students may participate in sports denied sports control by the Ohio Conference.
[SPEAKER_00]: The Congress has been under heavy pressure from various places, particularly Oberon College, to get rid of this rule.
[SPEAKER_00]: And threatened by a lawsuit now, they decided to take the pressure.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, Oberon is in violation of the rule and was... Oliver...
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I was just caught in a rundown when he went home and was finally declared out for falling down and scrambling outside of the baseline.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, we repealed the mail.
[SPEAKER_00]: It seems that Oberlin, who was in trouble with us for violating the mail rule and running Women in Exhibition track meet, was threatening to do this again this fall.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so some Oberlin students, if we had kept the evidence, replay that now,
[SPEAKER_00]: If, uh...
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know if he declared him out for any other baseline or anything.
[SPEAKER_00]: He just stopped running.
[SPEAKER_00]: Didn't look like the Rumpire made any ruling on that replay.
[SPEAKER_00]: The group of Oberlin students are going to sue the Ohio Atlantic Conference if they did not permit the women to run an exhibition track this far across country.
[SPEAKER_00]: So this is what provoked the special meeting.
[SPEAKER_00]: to either repeal the rule or to collect fund to fight any lawsuit in court.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, I've always felt this rule was, as long as I've been in this rule, good or bad, it had to go.
[SPEAKER_00]: It would have to go sooner or later, and the sooner the better.
[SPEAKER_00]: If you're just going to make trouble for yourself, you might as well get rid of it right now.
[SPEAKER_00]: There are a lot of arguments against it, saying it was going to dilute or wreck women's athletics, because if the women would go out for the men's team now, there wouldn't be any women.
[SPEAKER_00]: It would have a bad effect on the women's program.
[SPEAKER_00]: So there were quite a few arguments against it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Worcester was one of the strongest opponents, and a few other people.
[SPEAKER_00]: They kicked it around for quite a while.
[SPEAKER_00]: Finally, they brought it to a vote, and 26 to 1 voted for repeal of the Mayo rule.
[SPEAKER_00]: So it's out.
[SPEAKER_00]: The next thing to do was to create a committee to study the whole question of women's intercollegiate athletics in the Ohio Commons.
[SPEAKER_00]: And in conjunction with some of the women athletic directors, draw up some long-range plan
[SPEAKER_00]: deciding what sports would be suitable for co-educational participation and what ones would not, and make others study other matters, study Title IX, how this would apply, and so on.
[SPEAKER_00]: So Everett Bush, the president of the conference, then selected four people, two athletic directors and two faculty representatives to form this committee.
[SPEAKER_00]: He picked on Ed Sherman and Bob Strymer as the athletic directors, and George Andrews of Oberlin,
[SPEAKER_00]: Herman Langholz of Capital as the faculty people.
[SPEAKER_00]: Langholz demurred because he was recently linked to a new legislative committee out in the county.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't think he'd have time for it.
[SPEAKER_00]: So Everett Bush allowed him to get out, and then said he would name somebody later.
[SPEAKER_00]: We then adjourned, and David Jennings of Ohio Western came over, and we chatted for almost been a half an hour.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's telling me he's writing this volume on 20th century Ohio history.
[SPEAKER_00]: commissioned by the Howard Historical Society, and he's got $15,000 to do it.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's been working on it a couple of years, and he's had my Thom L. Johnson manuscript for a year or so, using that as one of his sources.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he spent about a half an hour telling me how great it was, how the Johnson manuscript, which he's read four or five times now, is so
[SPEAKER_00]: The research is so exhaustive.
[SPEAKER_00]: The interpretation of Johnson is so sound and valuable.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the methodology is so good.
[SPEAKER_00]: I gather all the data and I draw conclusions of my own, but I leave it open to the reader to draw his own conclusions.
[SPEAKER_00]: I give all the evidence there as to draw an object conclusion from what I draw.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's quite impressed by my fairness and objectivity in my research.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was really quite embarrassed that he thought it was so good.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he was borrowing large chunks of it, and he was really afraid that he might be borrowing so much that I'd think he was stealing it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the book came out, and he saw all this stuff of mine in there.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd get mad.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'd get mad at him.
[SPEAKER_00]: So he wanted to get assurance that I would not be mad.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I told him I wouldn't be mad.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I was, in fact, quite glad that I was able to help him.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the book was that, or the manuscript, that useful.
[SPEAKER_00]: and really flattered that he found it so sound, scholarly-wise.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, I was getting quite excited.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think I may have to get it out and read it over again myself.
[SPEAKER_00]: It sounds so good.
[SPEAKER_00]: While we were talking, he was telling me how great the thesis was on Tom Johnson, what happened.
[SPEAKER_00]: But Everett Bush comes up and sits down and interrupts us and said, say, Gene, how would you like to serve on that committee?
[SPEAKER_00]: the long-range planning committee to work with the women on developing a policy towards women's intercollegiate athletics.
[SPEAKER_00]: I've never been on any committee in that conference.
[SPEAKER_00]: None of the standing committees I've ever been questioned or asked, or no one has shown the slightest interest in putting me in any committee.
[SPEAKER_00]: And this is the last thing I ever thought they'd have me in one of the probably more important committees I've ever had.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was quite taken aback by it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't really know.
[SPEAKER_00]: I told them I hadn't had much service in the conference.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't think I had enough of a grasp of what... Well, I didn't say that.
[SPEAKER_00]: I just said my service was rather limited.
[SPEAKER_00]: Actually, I could do as good a job as anybody else, and probably better, since I have studied the thing maybe more than some.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was quite pleased to get the chance to do this, so I made a modest disavowal, but he pressed me, so I'm on the committee.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know about that.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm kind of looking forward to this.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know when we'll meet and what we'll do, but there's no timetable.
[SPEAKER_00]: Since we've repealed the rule now, there's no real timetable that we have to meet this fall.
[SPEAKER_00]: Jenny's went on and finally we broke up.
[SPEAKER_00]: He took me over to the library there and showed me where he does his research and showed me around the library.
[SPEAKER_00]: There was a nice audio-visual aid room, a laboratory almost, and a lovely television studio.
[SPEAKER_00]: Bernie Russey would drool if he saw it, and maybe he has drooled, but he has seen it.
[SPEAKER_00]: New cameras and a real good lighting system at those, at, uh,
[SPEAKER_00]: And whenever you call it down in the Basin of Andrews, they're on those network of wires and lights hooked down jerry-can fashion all over the place.
[SPEAKER_00]: So we looked around there, and about, oh, 5 or 4.30 or so, I left, and we departed, and I went to Bun's restaurant down where I had a hamburger and some french fries.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then I left for Newark.
[SPEAKER_00]: The plan was to see Woody English in Newark.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'd called him last March for an interview and he begged off because of his arthritis.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said maybe I'd come again this summer.
[SPEAKER_00]: But we decided I'd just go, Rita and I.
[SPEAKER_00]: It might be good if I just went up there and barged in.
[SPEAKER_00]: He wouldn't have a chance to say no.
[SPEAKER_00]: And maybe he'd talk to me if I was there and saw him.
[SPEAKER_00]: what I was like and what I was...
[SPEAKER_00]: I had a chance to explain what I was after.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I got in Newark around a quarter after six or so, wandered around, got lost a few times, but I only had to ask once or twice to find where North 11th Street was.
[SPEAKER_00]: I found it and went the wrong way.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went into a nice residential area.
[SPEAKER_00]: The other directions looked pretty bad, looked like kind of a downtown.
[SPEAKER_00]: congested, dirty area, so I didn't think they'd be down there, so I went the other way, but it turned out I should have gone the first way.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were down in this congested, dirty area, and kind of a crummy little house right next to a bar.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's a commercial area around there.
[SPEAKER_00]: A few homes, old homes, not very well kept up.
[SPEAKER_00]: Heavy traffic, motorcycles and cars racing around in a terrific racket.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I found the house and went up there, and there was a little old lady sitting in the front porch, rocking away, nice looking old lady.
[SPEAKER_00]: My God, could that be Woody English's mother?
[SPEAKER_00]: I talked to some lady on the phone when I talked to him, and later I talked to him, and he said it was his mother.
[SPEAKER_00]: I couldn't believe it would be his mother.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's 67.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was Woody English's mother, and there she was, 86 years old, as bright, cheerful, thin as a rail.
[SPEAKER_00]: Something emaciating, but pleasant, articulate, new baseball.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I had a delightful half-hour chat with Mrs. English.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, I wanted to go out and get the tape recorder and interview her, because Woody wasn't there.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was away in business, a state farm business, or going to the church or someplace.
[SPEAKER_00]: She thought he'd be back, but he wasn't, so I waited around a while for him, and I wanted to interview her.
[SPEAKER_00]: She laughed at that, but no, she didn't want to do that.
[SPEAKER_00]: It might upset Woody.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was very careful.
[SPEAKER_00]: She wouldn't even let me take her picture because he might not like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was really delightful.
[SPEAKER_00]: She's 86 years old.
[SPEAKER_00]: She told me a little bit about Woody English.
[SPEAKER_00]: His arthritis is terribly bad, I guess.
[SPEAKER_00]: so bad this last winter.
[SPEAKER_00]: His fingers and his shoulders were so bad and so he couldn't put his shirts on.
[SPEAKER_00]: She had to help him with his shirts.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she said, I wasn't feeling so well either this winter.
[SPEAKER_00]: So the two of them are mother and son, and none in very good health.
[SPEAKER_00]: I asked her if he had been married, because I knew he was married.
[SPEAKER_00]: It said so in the baseball daguerreotypes.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she said, he was married yesterday.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's not now.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't offer anymore, so I didn't press anymore.
[SPEAKER_00]: So apparently, he's either divorced.
[SPEAKER_00]: I presume that's what it is.
[SPEAKER_00]: But she knew his baseball career.
[SPEAKER_00]: She followed it with great interest and knew a lot about it.
[SPEAKER_00]: She told me how he broke into baseball or how he got into the big time.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd been playing locally here and some, I guess, a scout for the Giants.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't get it exactly, whether he scouted him in Newark or saw him play in Columbus and signed him to a contract.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's 17 years old now, must have been dying in 1924 or so.
[SPEAKER_00]: Mrs. English's brother, her husband died in 1918, that's one of the
[SPEAKER_00]: Sad story, she had to tell that her husband, who was a great baseball fan, knew everything about baseball, never lived to see his son make it big in the major leagues.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then she did have a brother, a man named Paul Cartner.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'll have to check up on him.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said he was with the Giants or signed with them or something.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know if he ever played or not.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she called up Paul Carpenter to see what he thought about all this.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he didn't like it much either.
[SPEAKER_00]: He thought, boy, he was too young.
[SPEAKER_00]: She finally called the guy, the scout in Columbus, and said, you know how old that boy is?
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, no, he's 17 years old.
[SPEAKER_00]: And you can't sign him up.
[SPEAKER_00]: I want him back.
[SPEAKER_00]: I want you to give him his release.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, oh, we can't do that.
[SPEAKER_00]: We signed him up.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, oh, yes, you can.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm controlling this.
[SPEAKER_00]: I want you to give him his release.
[SPEAKER_00]: I want you to give it right now.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's really funny hearing her talk so emphatically.
[SPEAKER_00]: She chuckles along with it.
[SPEAKER_00]: The impressive stance she took.
[SPEAKER_00]: So he gave him his release when he came back home.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then later on, her brother, Paul Cartner, said, well, he'll have plenty of offers and good ones too, so don't worry about that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Let's get over it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, it wasn't long, though, before a Toledo scout apparently came down and got it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he signed him, and this was all right with her.
[SPEAKER_00]: Maybe it was a year later, and he was older now, and she decided to reconcile herself with his playing professional baseball.
[SPEAKER_00]: So they'd signed it, and then she said, well, doesn't he get anything out of this?
[SPEAKER_02]: Meaning, your son, Woody, doesn't he get anything from this contract?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, you better give him something.
[SPEAKER_00]: So she slapped my knee and chuckled.
[SPEAKER_00]: She said, you know, they gave him $500.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she laughed, all because of her pressing the matter.
[SPEAKER_00]: She got $500.
[SPEAKER_00]: As we said, it wouldn't sound like much today, but it was a great thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then after a short time at Toledo, I guess, the Cubs learned about him.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they paid Toledo $50,000 plus two players for Woody English.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, she found his career very closely.
[SPEAKER_00]: She saw a couple World Series, I guess three of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: Those were all the World Series.
[SPEAKER_00]: He lived in Chicago permanently when I went up there, year-round residence there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he only came back on visits to Newark.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was born and raised in Newark.
[SPEAKER_00]: Or I guess he may have been born out in Alexandria a short distance away.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he lived in Newark at an early time.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I guess I didn't get too much on his career there.
[SPEAKER_00]: If I really had to get going, I'd drive back to Marietta.
[SPEAKER_00]: I couldn't really do all I wanted to do, but I did find out a few of the bare facts.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said he was just a frail kid when he broke in, and the Toledo scout said he looked like a piece of soap which had been
[SPEAKER_00]: He was in the washing all day long, something like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: He laughed at that, whatever the figure of speech was.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was so, well, apparently small and frail at that age when he broke in.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know how big he ever got, but he was pretty shriveled, I guess.
[SPEAKER_00]: They laughed at the figure of speech he was describing.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't come back to Newark until 1959.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was with, I don't know what he did after his plane crew in Chicago.
[SPEAKER_00]: He came back to Newark and got a job with State Farm Insurance, I think it was, and worked with them for a number of years.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she said he retired when he was 66 or so.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, that would have been just last year, as I have it.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was born in 1907.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he has been retired for some time, so maybe it was in 66 he retired.
[SPEAKER_00]: But these are the things I'll have to find out when I get to interviewing him.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then he's lived there with her.
[SPEAKER_00]: They didn't always live in this house.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know how long they lived in this house.
[SPEAKER_00]: They lived someplace else.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he's lived with her since he came back.
[SPEAKER_00]: Maybe there was something.
[SPEAKER_00]: Maybe his marriage broke up at this time he came back home.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he lives here with her now.
[SPEAKER_00]: There were four children, two boys and two girls.
[SPEAKER_00]: One of the boys and one of the girls are deceased.
[SPEAKER_00]: The other daughter is living in Newark and has a job with the county clerk in the county courthouse.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think she said she was married and they have a couple of children.
[SPEAKER_00]: At least there's somebody else in the town to look after them.
[SPEAKER_00]: I wanted to take her picture.
[SPEAKER_00]: I thought it would be great having this little old lady in her front porch of this rather run-down house.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she didn't want to do that.
[SPEAKER_00]: I asked her if she had any papers or pictures or scrapbooks or things that he did.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she said he brought an awful lot of stuff with him when he came back from Chicago in 1959.
[SPEAKER_00]: But you know, that very year that he got there in 1959, there was a terrible flood in Newark, and the water in the basement and all this stuff got ruined by the floodwaters.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were able to salvage a little bit, but not very much.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know, they tried drying it up, but they finally, I guess they threw it out.
[SPEAKER_00]: She didn't say what they did, but it was lost.
[SPEAKER_00]: So whatever he has, it isn't much.
[SPEAKER_00]: She was saying that just the other day,
[SPEAKER_00]: He does get a lot of requests from kids for pictures and autographs.
[SPEAKER_00]: And just the other day, I was asking her, I said, mother, where are all those old pictures?
[SPEAKER_00]: Are they in a box somewhere?
[SPEAKER_00]: And she said, well, maybe they are around here somewhere, but they haven't seen them lately.
[SPEAKER_00]: But there may still be something there.
[SPEAKER_00]: I asked her what?
[SPEAKER_00]: That would be the best time to try and come and see him.
[SPEAKER_00]: I just wanted to come and say hello this time so he'd get to know me and be less unwilling to see me for an interview.
[SPEAKER_00]: met me and realized I was serious and really wanted to talk baseball for a good purpose with him, he might be much more agreeable to doing this.
[SPEAKER_00]: So that was my purpose of coming there.
[SPEAKER_00]: I hoped that she would explain to him this, now that she had met me and knew that I was
[SPEAKER_00]: sincere in my efforts to have a good interview here, and she would ease the way for me.
[SPEAKER_00]: She said she'd be very happy to do that.
[SPEAKER_00]: I asked her what would be a good time to come up and talk to him.
[SPEAKER_00]: She said, well, just about now.
[SPEAKER_00]: You ought to just pop right in unexpectedly, and then he won't have a chance to say no.
[SPEAKER_00]: If you call him on the phone, he'll have a chance to say no.
[SPEAKER_00]: Exactly what Rita had said would be the way to do it.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's what we agreed.
[SPEAKER_00]: We'd trap him that way, she and I.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I'll come up about supper time sometime.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I asked her to advise him that we might be up some evening next week.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I want to talk to him.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I think that's what we may do.
[SPEAKER_00]: Rita will be home next week.
[SPEAKER_00]: She's been on her visitations all summer with Kathy.
[SPEAKER_00]: Kathy leaves for New Orleans tomorrow morning.
[SPEAKER_00]: She's packing out.
[SPEAKER_00]: They just got back late last night.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got home about 9 o'clock, and they got back about 11 o'clock from Charleston for another week of visitations.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we're as a grand worthy advisor of the rainbow this summer.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she's going this next week to the Supreme Assembly, which is a national rainbow gathering in New Orleans.
[SPEAKER_00]: They'll be meeting partners there by bus tomorrow morning, get down there Monday maybe, and then come back a week from Sunday.
[SPEAKER_00]: So Rita will be here, and she and I thought we might take a few trips, maybe go down and see Fred Blake in Beckley.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then we can do a little bit of touring, visit this restored village up at Monroeville, or wherever it is, and then maybe restore the village in the Ohio Historical Society grounds, visit the mounds in Newark, and maybe wrap up a day of touring
[SPEAKER_00]: by going over to Newark around 6 o'clock and dropping in at Woody English.
[SPEAKER_00]: So that's our plan.
[SPEAKER_00]: We might also take a trip down to West Virginia, as if she hadn't seen enough of it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Might go to Grantsville, find out about this.
[SPEAKER_00]: Guy Pollack and his Seneca books, if he is for real.
[SPEAKER_00]: I haven't heard from him for weeks about the Peck book, which I may be editing if they want to publish it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then we'll move on down to Beckley and perhaps a few other things.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, those are the highlights of that trip.
[SPEAKER_00]: I thought it'd be a good idea, while they were fresh in my memory, to say something about the Grove interview.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's a good idea to say something about every interview I have.
[SPEAKER_00]: I should be doing this.
[SPEAKER_00]: I haven't very much.
[SPEAKER_00]: But at least the Mrs. English interview, because she was really good, and I could have taped her very well if she had been agreeable.
[SPEAKER_00]: I could have had a good 45 minutes or an hour taped of her.
[SPEAKER_00]: It would have been very useful.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I couldn't force that on her.
[SPEAKER_00]: But maybe if I can get up there, Rita and I can get up there, we can get the two of them together and get a real good hour and a half with the both of them going.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because she can add an awful lot, as wives have done.
[SPEAKER_00]: Not mothers.
[SPEAKER_00]: I've never interviewed anybody's mother before.
[SPEAKER_00]: A lot of wives, but the same idea.
[SPEAKER_00]: OK, I haven't quite used up the whole tape.
[SPEAKER_00]: I see there's about
[SPEAKER_00]: a third of this side still remaining, but I think I've got all I have to say on this, so I'll be signing off.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is the day after the interview.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is Friday, the 19th of July, 1974, as I watched the Pirates of Atlanta ballot out here at 9.15 in the evening.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now I'm going to sign off and continue writing the chapter on the feud in the Van Johnson story.
[SPEAKER_00]: About halfway through this chapter on the feud with Comiskey and Johnson.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'll keep a wick on that now.
[SPEAKER_00]: So that'll be all for this evening.